Guide to the Sylvester Manor Archive 1649-1996 MSS.208
Fales Library and Special Collections
- Record Group IV: Horsford Family
  - Series H: Cornelia Conway Felton Horsford (Nellie)
    - Subseries 1: Correspondence
      - Foster, Dr. Charles C: Cambridge, MA, 1891 May 29; cuid3895 (Box 101, Folder 56)
        Sent From: “Dr. Charles A. Foster, 5 Riedesel Avenue, Cambridge, MA”
      - Galloway Terra-Cotta Company: Philadelphia, PA, 1923 May 11; cuid3896 (Box 101, Folder 57)
        Addressed To: “Miss [Cornelia Conway Felton] Horsford, Sylvester Manor, Shelter Island Heights, NY”
        Sent From: “Galloway Terra-Cotta Company, Walnut & Thirty Second Streets, Philadelphia, PA”
        In Reference To: Business / Professional; President Walter B. Galloway, Vice President M.E. Galloway, Secretary & Treasurer G. Galloway
      - Garden Nurseries: Narberth, PA, 1917 February 17; cuid3897 (Box 101, Folder 58)
        Addressed To: [Cornelia Conway Felton Horsford], “Sylvester Manor, Shelter Island, NY”
        Sent From: “Proprietor, A.E. Wohlert, The Garden Nurseries, Montgomery Avenue, Narberth, PA”
        In Reference To: Business / Gardens / Professional; 1 Flyer “Japanese Flowering Cherries, The One Ornamental Tree”; Japanese Flowering Cherries, Cherry Blossoms
        Typed, Printed & Handwritten in Pencil
      - Gardiner, Alexandra Diodati: Lausanne, Switzerland; Manche, France, 1926 March 11 & August 4; undated, circa 1932; cuid3898 (Box 101, Folder 12)
        2 Letters, 2 Envelopes with Postage, 1 Newsprint Clipping [Photocopy]
        Sent From: “Alexandra, Grand Hotel des Bains, Granville, Manche,” [France]; Beau-Rivage-Palace, Ouchy-Lausanne,” [Switzerland]; [Mrs. James Randall Creel, Alexandra Diodati Gardiner, Cousin of Cornelia Conway Felton Horsford]
        In Reference To: Family / Friendship / Personal / Social; Alice de Peyster; “A Recent Bride in Garden City, Long Island” Social News Clipping announcing Alexandra Diodati Gardiner’s marriage to James Randall Creel
        Measurements: 6” x 4” - 8.5” x 11”
      - Gardiner, Jon T: East Hampton, NY, 1929 November 18; 1930 July 14; cuid3899 (Box 101, Folder 59)
        Addressed To: “Dear Cousin,” “Miss [Cornelia Conway Felton] Horsford, Sylvester Manor, Shelter Island, NY / 27 Craigie Street, Cambridge, MA”
        Sent From: “Jon T. Gardiner, East Hampton, Long Island, NY,” [Cousin of Cornelia Conway Felton Horsford]
        In Reference To: Family / Financial / History / Personal / Social; History of New London; Lion Gardiner Memorial, Bank of New York and Trust Company
        Measurements: 6.25” x 3.5” - 6” x 7”
      - Gardiner, Lion: Gardiner's Island, NY, 1917 July 24; cuid3900 (Box 101, Folder 60)
        Sent From: “Lion Gardiner, Gardiner’s Island, Springs P.O., Suffolk County, NY”
        In Reference To: Friendship / Personal / Social / Travel; Visit Shelter Island, Adele
      - Gardiner, Nora L: Granada; Ouchy, Switzerland; Pau, France, 1926 August 11; 1928 March 6; [no year] April 11, circa 1926 - 1928; cuid3901 (Box 101, Folder 61)
        2 Letters, 2 Envelopes with Postage, 1 Postcard
        Addressed To: “Miss [Cornelia Conway Felton] Horsford, 27 Craigie Street, Cambridge, MA,” “Sylvester Manor, Shelter Island, NY”
        Sent From: “Nora L. [Gardiner], Beau Rivage-Palace, Ouchy-Lausanna,” [Switzerland]; "Granada (Alhambra) - Jardin de Lindaraja"; “Hotel de France, Pau,” [France]
        Measurements: 5.5" x 3.5" - 7” x 10.75”
      - Gardiner, Sarah Diodati: Bay Shore & New York, NY, 1885 January 18 - 1918 October 17; cuid3902 (Box 101, Folder 62)
        9 Letters, 9 Envelopes with Postage and Seals, 3 Photographs Addressed To: “Miss [Sarah Diodati] Gardiner, 3 East 82nd Street, New York, NY,” “45 East 57th Street, New York, NY,” “129 Whitney Avenue, New Haven, CT,” “Hotel de France et Choiseul, 239 Rue St. Honore, Paris,” [France], “Sagtikos Manor, Bay Shore, Long Island, NY,” “The Barrel-in-the-Pines, Lakewood, NY,” [Cousin of Cornelia Conway Felton Horsford] Sent From: “Cornelia [Conway Felton] Horsford, Boston, MA,” “27 Craigie Street,” [Cambridge, MA], “Sylvester Manor, Shelter Island, NY” In Reference To: Family / Friendship / Personal / Social / Travel; 3 B and W Wallet Photographs of Sylvester Manor Gardens, Grounds 60 Pages, Bound and Unbound Printed and Handwritten in Ink Measurements: 4.25” x 2.5” - 7” x 12”
      - Gardiner, Sarah Diodati: Bay Shore & New York, NY, 1918 October 26 - 1920 January 7; cuid3903 (Box 102, Folder 1)
        8 Letters, 7 Envelopes with Postage
        Addressed To: “Miss [Sarah Diodati] Gardiner, 3 East 82nd Street, New York, NY,” “Sagtikos Manor, Bay Shore, Long Island, NY," [Cousin of Cornelia Conway Felton Horsford]
        Sent From: “Cornelia [Conway Felton] Horsford, [27 Craigie Street], Cambridge, MA,” “Sylvester Manor, Shelter Island, NY”
        Measurements: 4” x 2.75” - 6.5” x 10.5”
      - Gardiner, Sarah Diodati: Bay Shore & New York, NY, 1920 March 7 - 1922 November 14; cuid3904 (Box 102, Folder 2)
        8 Letters, 8 Envelopes with Postage & Seals
        Addressed To: “Miss [Sarah Diodati] Gardiner, 3 East 82nd Street, New York, NY,” “Garden City Hotel, Garden City, NY,” “Sagtikos Manor, Bay Shore, Long Island, NY,” [Cousin of Cornelia Conway Felton Horsford]
        Sent From: “Cornelia [Conway Felton] Horsford, 27 Craigie Street, Cambridge, MA,” “Weldon Hotel, Greenfield, MA,” “Sylvester Manor, Shelter Island, NY”
        Measurements: 4.75” x 3” - 7” x 11”
      - Gardiner, Sarah Diodati: Bay Shore & New York, NY, 1922 November 27 - 1925 February 15; [no year] November 19, circa 1922 - 1925; cuid3905 (Box 102, Folder 3)
        Sent From: “Cornelia [Conway Felton] Horsford, Boston, MA,” “Sylvester Manor, Shelter Island, NY”
        Measurements: 4.75” x 3.5” - 6” x 8”
      - Gardiner, Sarah Diodati: Bay Shore & New York, NY, 1925 April 8 - 1926 June 13; cuid3906 (Box 102, Folder 4)
        9 Letters, 9 Envelopes, 1 Greeting Card, Ephemera, Notation, & Postage
        Addressed To: “Miss [Sarah Diodati] Gardiner, 3 East 82nd Street, New York, NY,” “Sagtikos Manor, Bay Shore, Long Island, NY,” [Cousin of Cornelia Conway Felton Horsford]
        Sent From: “Cornelia [Conway Felton] Horsford, 27 Craigie Street, Cambridge, MA,” “Sylvester Manor, Shelter Island, NY, ” “The Copley Plaza Hotel, Boston, MA”
        In Reference To: Family / Friendship / Personal / Social / Travel; Easter Greeting CardPressed Plants
        Measurements: 3” x 6” - 7.75” x 12”
      - Gardiner, Sarah Diodati: New York, NY, 1927 January 9 - December 23; 1928 May 18; cuid3907 (Box 102, Folder 5)
        8 Letters, 8 Envelopes with Ephemera & Postage
        Addressed To: “Miss [Sarah Diodati] Gardiner, 3 East 82nd Street, New York, NY,” [Cousin of Cornelia Conway Felton Horsford]
        Sent From: “Cornelia [Conway Felton] Horsford, 27 Craigie Street, Cambridge, MA”
        In Reference To: Family / Friendship / Personal / Social / Travel; 1 Newsprint Clipping “Shelter Island, Charles Lane Poor, Jr.,” Obituary [Photocopy]
      - Gardiner, Sarah Diodati: Bay Shore & New York, NY, 1922 February 5; 1928 July 10 - 1929 December 15; cuid3908 (Box 102, Folder 6)
        Sent From: “Cornelia [Conway Felton] Horsford, 27 Craigie Street, Cambridge, MA,” “Sylvester Manor, Shelter Island Heights, NY,” “The Savannah-Oglethorpe, Savannah, GA”
        Measurements: 4.75” x 3.75” - 7” x 10.5”
      - Gardiner, Sarah Diodati: Bay Shore & New York, NY, 1930 January 16 - 1931 April 5; cuid3909 (Box 102, Folder 7)
        9 Letters, 9 Envelopes with Notation & Postage
        Sent From: “Cornelia [Conway Felton] Horsford, 27 Craigie Street, Cambridge, MA,” “Sylvester Manor, Shelter Island Heights, NY,” “The Mohican Hotel, New London, CT,” “The Savannah-Oglethorpe, Savannah, GA”
        Measurements: 4.75” x 3” - 6.5” x 9.75”
      - Gardiner, Sarah Diodati: Bay Shore, NY; Paris, France, 1931 May 14 - September 28; cuid3910 (Box 102, Folder 8)
        Addressed To: “Miss [Sarah Diodati] Gardiner, Hotel de France et Choiseul, 239, Rue St. Honore, Paris,” [France], “Sagtikos Manor, Bay Shore, Long Island, NY,” [Cousin of Cornelia Conway Felton Horsford]
        Sent From: “Cornelia [Conway Felton] Horsford, Sylvester Manor, Shelter Island Heights, NY,” “The Malvern, Bar Harbor, ME”
        Measurements: 4.25” x 3” - 6.5” x 10”
      - Gardiner, Sarah Diodati: Bay Shore & New York, NY; Washington, D.C., 1931 October 12 - 1934 February 25; cuid3911 (Box 102, Folder 9)
        9 Letters, 9 Envelopes with Ephemera, Notation & Postage
        Addressed To: “Miss [Sarah Diodati] Gardiner, 3 East 82nd Street, New York, NY,” “Sagtikos Manor, Bay Shore, Long Island, NY / Mayflower Hotel, Washington, D.C.,” [Cousin of Cornelia Conway Felton Horsford]
        Sent From: “Cornelia [Conway Felton] Horsford, 27 Craigie Street, Cambridge, MA,” "Sylvester Manor, Shelter Island Heights, NY,” “The Copley Plaza, Boston, MA,” “The Mohican Hotel, New London, CT”
        In Reference To: Family / Friendship / Personal / Social / Travel; 1 Newsprint Clipping “How Storm Provided Timbers for Church,” Jonathan Havens Jr. [Photocopy]
        Measurements: 5.25" x 3.5" - 8” x 10”
      - Gardiner, Sarah Diodati: Bay Shore & New York, NY, 1934 November 20 - 1935 October 20; 1936 January 2; cuid3912 (Box 102, Folder 10)
        Addressed To: “Miss [Sarah Diodati] Gardiner, 3 East 82nd Street, New York, NY,” “Plaza Hotel, New York, NY,” “Sagtikos Manor, Bay Shore, Long Island, NY,” [Cousin of Cornelia Conway Felton Horsford]
        Sent From: “Cornelia [Conway Felton] Horsford, Sylvester Manor, Shelter Island Heights, NY”
        In Reference To: Family / Friendship / Personal / Social / Travel; Pressed Plants
        Measurements: 4” x 5” - 7.25” x 12”
      - Gardiner, Sarah Diodati: Évian- les- Bains, France; New York, NY, 1936 January 17 - 1939 March 21; cuid3913 (Box 102, Folder 11)
        11 Letters, 11 Envelopes with Postage
        Addressed To: “Miss [Sarah Diodati] Gardiner, 3 East 82nd Street, New York, NY,” “Hôtel Royal, Évian- les- Bains, France,” [Cousin of Cornelia Conway Felton Horsford]
        Sent From: “Cornelia [Conway Felton] Horsford, 27 Craigie Street, Cambridge, MA,” “Sylvester Manor, Shelter Island Heights, NY”
        Measurements: 4” x 5” - 7” x 9”
      - Gardiner, Sarah Diodati: Bay Shore & New York, NY, 1932 October 10; 1949 April 1; undated, circa 1940s; cuid3914 (Box 102, Folder 12)
        Addressed To: “Miss [Sarah Diodati] Gardiner, 3 East 82nd Street, New York, NY,” “Sagtikos Manor, Bay Shore, NY,” [Cousin of Cornelia Conway Felton Horsford]; “Miss Gertrude [Hubbard Horsford Fiske] Weston, MA,” [Sister of Cornelia Conway Felton Horsford]
        Sent From: “Miss [Cornelia Conway Felton] Horsford, Sylvester Manor, Shelter Island Heights, NY”; “[Sarah Diodati] Gardiner, 3 East 82nd Street, New York, NY”
        Measurements: 4” x 3.25” - 6.5” x 10”
      - Gatschet, Albert Samuel: Washington, D.C., 1897 February 2 & 5; cuid3915 (Box 103, Folder 1)
        Addressed To: “Miss [Cornelia Conway Felton] Horsford, 27 Craigie Street, Cambridge, MA; “[Mr. W. of McGee], Mr. Albert [Samuel] Gatschet”
        Sent From: “Albert [Samuel] Gatschet, Smithsonian Institution, Bureau of American Ethnology, Washington, D.C.”; “Cornelia [Conway Felton] Horsford”
        In Reference To: Academic / Education / Business / Professional; National Geographic Magazine, Norumbega
        Measurements: 5.25” x 4.25” - 10.5” x 7.25”
        Albert Samuel Gatschet (October 3, 1832, Beatenberg, Canton of Bern – March 16, 1907) was a Swiss-American ethnologist who trained as a linguist in the universities of Bern and Berlin, but later moved to the United States in order to study Native American languages, a field in which he was a pioneer. The Albert Samuel Gatschet Papers (1828-1906) are preserved in the National Anthropological Archives at the Smithsonian Institution in Washington, D.C.
      - Gouwe and Helena: Honolulu, HI; Shelter Island, NY, 1928 March 2 - 3; undated, circa 1928; cuid3916 (Box 103, Folder 2)
        2 Letters, 1 Envelope, 1 Postcard with Postage
        Addressed To: “Miss Cornelia [Conway Felton] Horsford, 27 Craigie Street, Cambridge, MA,” “Sylvester Manor, Shelter Island, NY”
        Sent From: “Gouwe and Helena,” [Honolulu, HI], “Sylvester Manor, Shelter Island, NY,” [Nephew & Niece of Cornelia Conway Felton Horsford]
        Measurements: 5.5” x 3.25” - 6” x 10”
      - Havens, Kate E: Stamford, CT, 1932 September 12; cuid3917 (Box 103, Folder 5)
        Addressed To: “Miss Cornelia [Conway Felton] Horsford, Manor House [Sylvester Manor], Shelter Island, Suffolk County, NY”
        Sent From: “Miss [Kate E.] Havens, Stamford, CT”
        In Reference To: Friendship / History / Personal / Social; Local & Shelter Island History
        Measurements: 6.5” x 3.5” - 7” x 12”
      - Horsford, Eben Norton: Germany; Shelter Island, NY, 1882 September 27; 1890 July 22; cuid3918 (Box 103, Folder 5a)
        Addressed To: “Miss Cornelia [Conway Felton] Horsford, 27 Craigie Street, Cambridge, MA,” “Lenox, Berkshire County, MA”
        Sent From: “Eben Norton Horsford” [Father of Cornelia Conway Felton Horsford]
        Measurements: 5” x 3” - 5.25” x 8.25”
      - Horsford, Jerediah: [Moscow, NY], undated, circa 1870 - 1875; cuid3919 (Box 103, Folder 3)
        Addressed To: “My dear Grandfather,” [Jerediah Horsford, Father of Eben Norton Horsford, Unidentified Location, Possibly Moscow, NY]
        Sent From: “Nellie,” [Cornelia Conway Felton Horsford]
      - Horsford, Jerediah: [Brooklyn, NY], 1866 June 7; 1867 December 25; undated, post 1944; cuid3920 (Box 103, Folder 8)
        4 Envelopes, 2 Letters, 1 Transcription with Notation [Photocopy]
        Addressed To: “Miss Nellie Horsford, Cambridge, MA,” [Cornelia Conway Felton Horsford]
        Sent From: “Jerediah Horsford,” [Grandfather of Cornelia Conway Felton Horsford]
        In Reference To: Family / Friendship / Personal / Social / Travel; Merry Christmas
        Measurements: 2.75” x 1.75” - 8.5” x 11”
      - Horsford, Mary Katherine (Kate): Cambridge, MA; Colorado Springs, CO, 1881 June 13 - 1925 June 26; undated, circa 1925; cuid3921 (Box 103, Folder 10)
        8 Letters, 2 Envelopes with Postage
        Addressed To: “Miss Cornelia [Conway Felton] Horsford, 27 Craigie Street, Cambridge, MA,” “Sylvester Manor, Shelter Island Heights, NY”
        Sent From: “Kate, 27 Craigie Street, Cambridge, MA,” [Brownlands], [Georgetown, Washington, D.C.], [Mary Katherine Horsford, Sister of Cornelia Conway Felton Horsford]
        Measurements: 5.5” x 3.5” - 10” x 6.5”
      - Horsford, Mary Leila (Lilian): Cambridge, MA; Chocorua, NH, 1902 June 7 - 1926 August 24; undated, post 1944; cuid3922 (Box 103, Folder 11)
        Sent From: “Lilian, 24 Quincy Street, Cambridge, MA,” “Chocorua, NH,” [Mary Leila Horsford]
        In Reference To: Family / Friendship / Poetry / Personal / Social; 1 Newsprint Clipping “Elizabeth Aged Nine” by Margaret E. Sangster [Photocopy]; 1 Obituary, “Dr. William Gilson Farlow [3 Copies]
        Measurements: 3” x 2” - 8.5” x 11”
      - Horsford, Phoebe Dayton Gardiner: Cambridge, MA, 1881-1883; cuid3923 (Box 103, Folder 12)
        10 Letters, 5 Envelopes with Postage
        Addressed To: “Gardiner [Greene] Hubbard, Esq., Miss Cornelia [Conway Felton] Horsford, 1328 Connecticut Avenue, Washington, D.C.”; “W.B. Van Rensselaer, Esq., Miss Cornelia Horsford, 15 Washington Avenue, Albany, NY”
        Sent From: “Mamma, 27 Craigie Street, Cambridge,” [MA] [Phoebe Dayton Gardiner Horsford, Mother of Cornelia Conway Felton Horsford]
      - Horsford, Phoebe Dayton Gardiner: Cambridge, MA, 1883 February 1 - 11; undated, circa 1883; cuid3924 (Box 103, Folder 13)
        Addressed To: “℅ Robert Ogden Doremus, 123 Lexington Avenue, New York, NY”; “Gardiner [Greene] Hubbard, Esq., Miss Cornelia [Conway Felton] Horsford, 1328 Connecticut Avenue, Washington, D.C.”; “Professor Eben Norton Horsford, Misses Horsford, Union Square Hotel, New York, NY”
      - Horsford, Phoebe Dayton Gardiner: Cambridge, MA, 1883 February - September; undated, circa 1883; cuid3925 (Box 103, Folder 14)
        8 Letters, 6 Envelopes with Postage
        Addressed To: “℅ Robert Ogden Doremus, Miss C.F. Horsford, 123 Lexington Avenue, New York, NY”; “Miss Cornelia [Conway Felton] Horsford, Albany, NY, Kindness of Benjamin R. Curtis, Esq.,”; “Sylvester Manor, Shelter Island, NY”
      - Horsford, Phoebe Dayton Gardiner: Cambridge & Plymouth, MA, 1885 January 11 - 1892 March 17; cuid3926 (Box 103, Folder 15)
        8 Letters, 7 Envelopes with Ephemera & Postage
        Addressed To: “W.B. Van Rensselaer, Miss Cornelia Horsford, 15 Washington Avenue, Albany, NY”; “Mrs. President Tyler [Julia Gardiner Tyler], Miss C. Horsford, 715 East Grace Street, Richmond, VA”
        Sent From: “Mamma, 27 Craigie Street, Cambridge,” [MA] “Chilton Downs, Plymouth, MA,” [Phoebe Dayton Gardiner Horsford, Mother of Cornelia Conway Felton Horsford]
        In Reference To: Family / Friendship / Personal / Social; 1 Newsprint Clipping “Engagement of Miss Coralie Livingston Gardiner, daughter of John Lyon Gardiner, to Alexander R. Cox, of London” [Photocopy]; 1 Newsprint Clipping “Mrs. A.M. Mosher gave a breakfast to Mr. Frederick Douglass” [Original]
        Measurements: 4.35” x 3” - 4.5” x 7”
      - Horsford, Phoebe Dayton Gardiner: Cambridge, MA, 1892 March 15 - 1895 March 20; cuid3927 (Box 103, Folder 16)
        6 Letters, 7 Envelopes with Postage
        Addressed To: “Miss Cornelia [Conway Felton] Horsford, ℅ Charles J. Bell, Esq., 1327 Connecticut Avenue, Washington, D.C.,” “Manhasset House, Shelter Island, NY”; “W.B. Van Rensselaer, Miss Cornelia Horsford, 15 Washington Avenue, Albany, NY”
        Measurements: 4.75” x 3.75” - 6.5” x 8.75”
      - Horsford, Phoebe Dayton Gardiner: Cambridge, MA, 1895 March 19 - 25; cuid3928 (Box 103, Folder 17)
        Addressed To: “Miss Cornelia [Conway Felton] Horsford, ℅ Charles J. Bell, Esq., 1327 Connecticut Avenue, Washington, D.C."
        Measurements: 3.5” x 5.25” - 6.5” x 8.75”
      - Horsford, Phoebe Dayton Gardiner: Cambridge, MA, 1895 March 25 - 1899 October 12; cuid3929 (Box 103, Folder 18)
        6 Letters, 10 Envelopes with Notation & Postage, 1 Calling / Visiting Card
        Addressed To: “Andrew Fiske, Esq., Miss Cornelia [Conway Felton] Horsford, Weston, MA,” “27 Craigie Street, Cambridge, MA,” “℅ Charles J. Bell, Esq., 1327 Connecticut Avenue, Washington, D.C.,” “The Stafford, Baltimore, MD”; “Mr. Arnold”
        In Reference To: Family / Friendship / Personal / Social; Rumford Chemical Works
        Measurements: 3.5” x 2.5” - 6.5” x 8.75”
      - Horsford, Phoebe Dayton Gardiner: Cambridge, MA, 1890 May 28 - 1892 September 25; 1899 November 19 & 30; cuid3930 (Box 103, Folder 19)
        Addressed To: “Charles J. Bell, Esq., Miss Horsford, 1327 Connecticut Avenue, Washington, D.C.,” “Gardiner M. Lane, Esq., Miss Cornelia [Conway Felton] Horsford, West Manchester, MA,” “Miss Cornelia Horsford, 27 Craigie Street, Cambridge, MA,” “Sylvester Manor, Shelter Island Heights, NY,” “W.B. Van Renssalaer, Esq., Miss Cornelia Horsford, 15 Washington Avenue, Albany, NY”; “Mr. Arnold”
        Measurements: 3.5” x 2.75” - 4.5” x 7”
      - Horsford, Phoebe Dayton Gardiner: Cambridge, MA, 1900 March 27 - July 16; undated, circa 1900; cuid3931 (Box 103, Folder 20)
        4 Letters, 5 Envelopes with Postage
        Addressed To: “Miss Cornelia [Conway Felton] Horsford, ℅ Charles J. Bell, Esq., 1327 Connecticut Avenue, Washington, D.C.,” “℅ Gardiner M. Lane, Esq., West Manchester, MA,” “Fifth Avenue Hotel,” [New York, NY]
        Measurements: 3.5” x 2.75” - 4.5” x 6.75”
      - Horsford, Phoebe Dayton Gardiner: Cambridge, MA; Newport, RI, [no year] January 9 - May 29, circa 1885; cuid3932 (Box 103, Folder 21)
        6 Letters, 9 Letters with Notation & Postage
        Addressed To: “Miss Cornelia [Conway Felton] Horsford, 27 Craigie Street, Cambridge, MA,” “Mrs. President Tyler (Julia Gardiner), Miss Cornelia Horsford, 715 East Grace Street, Richmond, VA,” “Sylvester Manor (Abbey Manor), Shelter Island, Suffolk County,” [NY], “W.B. Van Rensselaer, Esq., Miss Cornelia Horsford, 15 Washington Avenue, Albany, NY”
        Sent From: “Mamma, 27 Craigie Street, Cambridge,” [MA], “Aquidneck Island, Newport, RI,” [Phoebe Dayton Gardiner Horsford, Mother of Cornelia Conway Felton Horsford]
        Measurements: 4.75” x 2.5” - 5” x 8”
      - Horsford, Phoebe Dayton Gardiner: Cambridge, MA, 1883 January 30 - 1886 January 9; undated, circa 1883 - 1886; cuid3933 (Box 103, Folder 22)
        Addressed To: “℅ Dr. Robert Ogden Doremus, 123 Lexington Avenue, New York, NY,”“℅ Gardiner [Greene] Hubbard, Esq., 1328 Connecticut Avenue, Washington, D.C., “ “℅ Professor Eben Norton Horsford, Riggs House, Washington, D.C.,” “℅ W.B. Van Rensselaer, Esq., 15 Washington Avenue, Albany, NY,” “Miss Cornelia [Conway Felton] Horsford, Shelter Island, Suffolk County, NY
        Sent From: “Mamma, 27 Craigie Street, Cambridge,” [MA], [Phoebe Dayton Gardiner Horsford, Mother of Cornelia Conway Felton Horsford]
      - Horsford, Phoebe Dayton Gardiner: Cambridge, MA; Newport, RI, [no year] July 4; undated, circa 1880s; cuid3934 (Box 103, Folder 23)
        20 Letters with Indentation, 1 Envelope
        Addressed To: “My darling Nellie,” [Cornelia Conway Felton Horsford]
        Measurements: 3” x 4” - 5” x 8”
      - Horsford, Phoebe Dayton Gardiner: Cambridge, MA, [no year] May 29; 1884 September 25; 1893 October 13; undated, circa 1880s; cuid3935 (Box 103, Folder 24)
        12 Letters, 7 Envelopes with Postage
        Addressed To: “Miss Cornelia [Conway Felton] Horsford, Bay View House, Shelter Island Heights, Shelter Island, NY,” “℅ Andrew Fiske, Esq., Weston, MA,” “W.B. Van Rensselaer, Esq., Miss Cornelia Horsford, 15 Washington Avenue, Albany, NY”
        62 Pages, Bound & Unbound
        Measurements: 4.5” x 3.5” - 6.75” x 9”
      - Horsford Curtis, Mary Gardiner (Mamie): Cambridge, MA, 1872 August 30; 1886 September 10 & 11; [no year], July 21, circa 1880s; cuid3936 (Box 103, Folder 9)
        3 Letters, 2 Envelopes with Postage, 1 Calling / Visiting Card
        Sent From: “Mamie, Boston / Cambridge / Chilton Downs [Plymouth] / Ventfort Teviot House, MA,” “Mrs. Benjamin R. Curtis, Jr.,” [Mary Gardiner Horsford Curtis, Sister of Cornelia Conway Felton Horsford]
        Measurements: 3.5” x 2.25” - 4.5” x 7”
      - Hubbard Bell, Grace: New York, NY, 1931 October 1; cuid3937 (Box 103, Folder 25)
        Addressed To: “Miss [Cornelia Conway Felton] Horsford, Sylvester Manor, Shelter Island, NY”
        Sent From: “Grace [Hubbard Bell], 901 Lexington Avenue, New York, NY” [Daughter of Gardiner G. Hubbard, Gertrude M. McCurdy Hubbard, Wife of Charles J. Bell]
        Measurements: 5.5” x 3.5” - 6.75” x 10.75”
      - Insurance Company of North America: [Philadelphia, PA], undated, circa 1880 - 1944; cuid3938 (Box 104, Folder 1)
        Addressed To: “Insurance Company of North America”
        Sent From: “Cornelia [Conway Felton] Horsford”
        In Reference To: Business / Financial / Legal / Professional; Phoebe Dayton Gardiner Horsford, Shelter Island Insurance
      - Irwin, Agnes: [Cambridge, MA], undated, circa 1890 - 1910; cuid3939 (Box 103, Folder 4)
        1 Letter, 1 Envelope with Ephemera
        Addressed To: “Miss Cornelia [Conway Felton] Horsford, [27] Craigie Street,” [Cambridge, MA]
        Sent From: “Agnes Irwin” [Cambridge, MA]
        In Reference To: Friendship / Personal / Poetry / Social; 1 Clipping “Roger Wolcott” by Sarah Warner Brooks [Photocopy]
        Measurements: 4.75" x 3" - 8.5” x 11”
      - James, William: [Cambridge, MA], 1888 May 2; 1889 January 8; [no year] January 18 & March 31, circa 1888; cuid3940 (Box 104, Folder 2)